## Hien Mai

1589 Summersweet Cir, Lewis Center, OH 43035 (Mobile) 614.625.3142 (Email) <a href="mailto:hienm9@gmail.com">hienm9@gmail.com</a>

## **Professional Summary**

I am a recent graduate of the Ohio State University full-stack web development program with newly developed skills in JavaScript, CSS, and MERN stack. After working as a Quality Assurance (QA) professional for over 10 years, I decided that it was time for a career change. I love learning new technologies and developing friendly web user applications.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

- Over ten years of experience in Software Testing of User Interface Web-based applications, and Mobile Device applications.
- Worked on different domains like e-Commerce, Public Safety, Health Care
- Strong experience in and knowledge of all phases of the Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC), Agile and Waterfall Testing Methodologies.
- Experience in automation using Selenium with Pytest.
- Experience in Performing Backend API Testing.
- Highly exposed to Defect Management process and Defect Tracking systems such as Jira, ALM.
- Experience in working with onsite-offshore team model projects.
- Excellent analytical and troubleshooting skills.

# **Lead Quality Assurance Analyst Duet Health)**

DeliverHealth (formerly

February 2019-Present

Columbus, OH

Lead QA team for all testing efforts across multiple product lines in Health Care Solutions for Patients on Web applications and Mobile Device applications.

#### **Responsibilities:**

- Perform regression, feature, smoke testing, APIs testing software for web, mobile, and tablet devices
- Collaborate with the product, software development, designers, and the company leadership to ensure the highest quality products are delivered to clients
- Automate test cases using Selenium with Pytest
- Use Jira for Defect Management
- Create and update test plans
- Mentor QA team

**Quality Assurance Analyst UAT** June 2017– Jan 2018 JPMorgan Chase Columbus, OH Worked in conjunction with the Product Management and Development teams for iManage, Passport-Spend, and Passport-Gold, to ensure that applications meet requirements and are of high quality.

#### **Responsibilities:**

- Reviewed Business Requirements, Functional Specifications understand the functional and technical requirements.
- Created detailed test scripts based on the requirements in Gherkin style.
- Tested the application and verified the requirements were successfully met.
- Executed test scripts and documented defects.
- Worked with users to complete test execution.

#### **Lead Quality Assurance Analyst**

February 2011- December 2016

**Emergitech Inc.** 

Columbus, OH

Lead QA team for all testing efforts across multiple product lines in a Public Safety Solutions company. Products included .NET VoIP 9-1-1 system and mapping, Mobile data computing, state/NCIS access, cloud-based solutions for Computer Assisted Dispatch (CAD), Records Management Systems (RMS), Jail Management and other Public Safety solutions on Android and IOs devices.

#### **Responsibilities:**

- Analyzed requirements with the project team to plan for testing.
- Developed, maintained and executed test scripts and test cases.
- Performed unit, functional and system testing.
- Performed test case reviews to ensure scenarios accurately reflect requested business functionality.
- Created detailed documentation for defects and test result summaries.
- Prepared release documentation as needed for training end users.
- Attended Sprint planning, Daily Stand-up, and the Sprint Retrospective on Agile projects.
- Attended functional requirement reviews to provide input on functional requirements, product designs, schedules and potential issues.
- Developed automation and manual test script for 911 VoIP application in VB using Test Complete tool.
- Worked with Mantis, JIRA, TigerPaw, Team Foundation Server/Microsoft Test Manager tools for test and defect management.
- Scheduled and prioritized test efforts on simultaneous Agile and Waterfall development projects.
- Responsible for setting up/maintaining the QA test environment for each project (including test data, software).
- Provided weekly status updates regarding test progress, results to senior management.
- Held regular team meetings to monitor the progress of testing efforts.
- Mentored QA team members.

#### **Lead Quality Assurance Analyst**

Epicor – (formerly NSB Group) Columbus, OH

August 2004 – February 2011

Promoted to serve as lead QA tester, overseeing the daily testing activities of the Quality Assurance Analysts. Accountable for the quality of the Retail POS system delivered with high quality.

#### **Responsibilities:**

- Planned project deliverables testing, and responsible for the team members' deliverables in system testing, integration testing, and regression testing, on client/server applications using .Net.
- Performed system, unit, performance, and regression testing.
- Worked with the development team on resolving issues.
- Created detailed test scripts on new functionality, based on business requirements document and development release document.
- Created and executed automation and manual test scripts, and troubleshoot issues
- Worked with issue tracking tools, I-service and Siebel, to report and track issues.
- Created automated test scripts in VB using Test Partner tool.
- Ran automation and manual scripts on QA updates and Regression testing.
- Scheduled and prioritized test efforts on Waterfall projects.
- Responsible for the release of the POS product to clients.
- Responsible for verifying and deploying product software patch updates on a regular basis.
- Maintained test scripts, based on issues reported and enhancements.
- Setup the QA test environment for each release (including test data, hardware, software).
- Provided regular progress and status reports on QA activities to the QA manager.
- Responsible for training, on-boarding, and mentoring new hires to the QA team.
- Supported offshore QA.

#### **Quality Assurance Analyst**

NSB Group

August 2002 – August 2004

Columbus, OH

- Created and executed automation and manual test scripts; troubleshoot issues
- Worked with issue tracking tools, I-service and Siebel, to report and track issues.
- Worked with the development team on resolving issues.

### **SKILLS**

**QA**: Test Planning, Jira, SDLC, Scrum, Agile, Automation Selenium with Pytest, Software Testing, Git

Front-End: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Jquery, Bootstrap, Responsive design

Back-End: APIs, Node, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, MERN stack

## **EDUCATION**

- St. John Fisher College, Rochester, NY BS in Mathematics, Minor in Computer Science, 2001
- Ohio State University coding bootcamp, Columbus, OH Full Stack Web Development, 2022
- Classes taken towards a professional career: QA process through SPD/IIST conference.